{
    "id": "d9443e4f677a436181ddaa6698a8f672",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I have just …………………. the work.",
            "description": "Begun is the past participle of begin. We use the past participle form of the verb after has/have.",
            "answers": [
                "began",
                "begun",
                "begin"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………. David Copperfield.",
            "description": "The present perfect is commonly used to talk about a finished event when its time is not mentioned.",
            "answers": [
                "read",
                "have read",
                "had read"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………….. my lunch.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about finished events whose effect is still felt in the present.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "have had"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. him for a long time.",
            "description": "The present perfect is common with the time expressions since and for.",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "knew",
                "have known"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………….. to his native place yesterday.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events.",
            "answers": [
                "went",
                "has gone",
                "had gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………… a lot for me when he was alive.",
            "description": "The present perfect is more common when there is no time reference.",
            "answers": [
                "did",
                "has done",
                "had done"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… the Taj Mahal.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "never saw",
                "have never seen",
                "never see"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………. ill since last week.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "has been",
                "was",
                "is"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They …………………………… the marks yet.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "did not calculate",
                "have not calculated",
                "had not calculated"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. two movies since morning.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "watched",
                "have watched",
                "had watched"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………….. for an hour and then I went home.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "waited",
                "have waited",
                "had waited"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}